<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>org:xplatformer on jrbeverly</title><link>/tags/orgxplatformer/</link><description>Recent content in org:xplatformer on jrbeverly</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 19:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/orgxplatformer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>readme</title><link>/2020/04/xplatformer-readme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 19:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/04/xplatformer-readme/</guid><description>XPlatformer Summary XPlatformer is a simple video game reminiscent of the classic side-scrolling arcade game, using the XLib API. The point of the game is to control a character through a terrain to meet an objective. The project makes use of the XLib API (XOrg) and focus on code that was developed to accomplish tasks for the assignment task.
Acknowledgements The project icon is retrieved from kenney.nl. The original source material has been altered for the purposes of the project.</description></item><item><title>xplatformer-workspace</title><link>/2018/11/xplatformer-xplatformer-workspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:52:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/11/xplatformer-xplatformer-workspace/</guid><description>XPlatformer-Workspace Summary A meta-repository for facilitating development of the many-repository XPlatformer project.
Getting Started XPlatformer-Workspace is a git-submodules oriented approach for dealing with the multiple repositories of the XPlatformer project (XPlatformer / XGameLib / XSamples). The project provides all the repositories in one, using vagrant-desktop to provide an X11 development environment. You can clone all the repositories using the --recursive directive of git as such:
git clone --recursive git@gitlab:.../XPlatformer-Workspace.git Or if the repository has already been cloned, you can use:</description></item><item><title>docker-xwindow</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-docker-xwindow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 23:01:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-docker-xwindow/</guid><description>Dockerized X Window System Summary A super small image with X Window System development libraries installed. The project icon is from cre.ativo mustard, HK from the Noun Project
NOTE: This image is marked EOL, and use is discouraged.
Usage You can use this image locally with docker run, calling g++ to build X Window System applications:
docker run -v $(pwd):/media/ jrbeverly/xwindow:privileged g++ myxapp.cpp -o xapp Gitlab You can setup a build job using .</description></item><item><title>vagrant-desktop-x11</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-vagrant-desktop-x11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:52:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-vagrant-desktop-x11/</guid><description>Vagrant X11 Desktop Summary Provide a method of reproducible graphical development environments based on Linux. This repository provides a X11 Linux Desktop environment for the development of the XPlatformer project.
Getting Started You can use this locally with vagrant up, calling as such:
vagrant --name=mydesktop up However It is recommended to use the script create.sh for the first run to ensure all necessary arguments are provided. The provided arguments creates a settings.</description></item><item><title>xsamples</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-xsamples/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:46:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-xsamples/</guid><description>XSamples Summary XSamples provides a collection of XWindows starter code that works with the XGameLib library. The XGameLib library powers the XPlatformer project. All the examples make use of the XLib API (XOrg) and focus on code that was developed in the XPlatformer project (or planned to be used). The point of the examples is to demonstrate how to use the XGameLib library.
Getting Started To make (&amp;ldquo;compile and link&amp;rdquo;) an example, use the included makefile with the name of cpp file passed as a variable.</description></item><item><title>xgamelib</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-xgamelib/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:46:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-xgamelib/</guid><description>XGameLib Summary XGameLib is a simple video game library used in the development of a classic side-scrolling arcade game, using the XLib API. The point of the game is to control a character through a terrain to meet an objective. The project makes use of the XLib API (XOrg) and focus on code that was developed to accomplish tasks for the assignment task.
Components Component Filename Description Spritesheet Spritesheet.</description></item><item><title>xplatformer</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-xplatformer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-xplatformer/</guid><description>XPlatformer Summary XPlatformer is a simple video game reminiscent of the classic side-scrolling arcade game, using the XLib API. The point of the game is to control a character through a terrain to meet an objective. The project makes use of the XLib API (XOrg) and focus on code that was developed to accomplish tasks for the assignment task.
Getting Started To make (&amp;ldquo;compile and link&amp;rdquo;) an example, you can use bazel to build and run the project:</description></item></channel></rss>