<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thefriending on jrbeverly</title><link>/tags/thefriending/</link><description>Recent content in thefriending on jrbeverly</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 19:38:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/thefriending/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>readme</title><link>/2020/04/thefriending-readme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 19:38:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/04/thefriending-readme/</guid><description>README for the Friending Community Friending Summary Friending is an online dating, friendship, and social networking mobile application that features user-created questionnaires. Friending has two primary features: joining groups to find people similar to you or signing up for events happening in your local area. Friending is a prototype built with the Proto.io application prototyping tool.
The Friending prototype was built as part of a requirements specification project.</description></item><item><title>website</title><link>/2020/01/thefriending-website/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 02:42:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/01/thefriending-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>This repository contains the source for the webpage &lt;a href="https://friending.jrbeverly.dev/">friending.jrbeverly.dev&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The webpage is built off the Hugo template by by &lt;a href="http://www.Themefisher.com">themefisher&lt;/a> used under &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">CC by 3.0&lt;/a> - Alterations to theme have been made to the underlying template.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those changes are made available in the &lt;code>themes/vex&lt;/code> directory.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>friending</title><link>/2017/05/thefriending-friending/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:07:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/thefriending-friending/</guid><description>Friending is an online dating, friendship, and social networking mobile application that features user-created questionnaires. Friending has two primary features: joining groups to find people similar to you or signing up for events happening in your local area. Friending is a prototype built with the Proto.io application prototyping tool. The Friending prototype was built as part of a requirements specification project. The project focused on the development of a user manual around a fictional matchmaking application called Friending. The application centered around user-created questionnaires that could be used to find relationship matches. The user manual was designed with the goal of &lt;em>deceiving&lt;/em> the reader into believing that the application existed. A project vision document and set of user requirements guided the development of scenarios and use cases for the application. The fully-interactive high-fidelity prototype created for the requirements specification project is provided in this repository, available as a standalone HTML page.</description></item><item><title>user-guide</title><link>/2017/05/thefriending-user-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:07:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/thefriending-user-guide/</guid><description>The Friending user manual provided as a web resource generated from the user manual. The user guide provides info and tips to help you understand the mobile application as a web resource, instead of the standard PDF representation of the user manual. The method used to convert the user manual can be viewed in the &lt;code>build/&lt;/code> directory.</description></item><item><title>manual</title><link>/2017/05/thefriending-manual/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:07:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/thefriending-manual/</guid><description>The Friending user manual provides info and tips to help you understand the mobile application. The project is the actualization of a user vision and set of requirements to construct a matchmaking application. The User Manual encodes these requirements as scenarios and use cases, while the Friending prototype presents a high-fidelity vision of the matchmaking application.</description></item></channel></rss>