<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>xplatformer on jrbeverly</title><link>/tags/xplatformer/</link><description>Recent content in xplatformer on jrbeverly</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 19:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/xplatformer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>readme</title><link>/2020/04/xplatformer-readme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 19:26:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2020/04/xplatformer-readme/</guid><description>README for the XPlatformer Community XPlatformer Summary XPlatformer is a simple video game reminiscent of the classic side-scrolling arcade game, using the XLib API. The point of the game is to control a character through a terrain to meet an objective. The project makes use of the XLib API (XOrg) and focus on code that was developed to accomplish tasks for the assignment task.</description></item><item><title>xplatformer-workspace</title><link>/2018/11/xplatformer-xplatformer-workspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:52:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2018/11/xplatformer-xplatformer-workspace/</guid><description>A meta-repository for facilitating development of the many-repository XPlatformer project.</description></item><item><title>docker-xwindow</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-docker-xwindow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 23:01:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-docker-xwindow/</guid><description>A super small image with &lt;a href="https://www.x.org/wiki/">X Window System&lt;/a> development libraries installed. The project icon is from &lt;a href="docs/icon/icon.json">cre.ativo mustard, HK from the Noun Project&lt;/a> &lt;strong>NOTE: This image is marked EOL, and use is discouraged.&lt;/strong></description></item><item><title>vagrant-desktop-x11</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-vagrant-desktop-x11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:52:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-vagrant-desktop-x11/</guid><description>Provide a method of reproducible graphical development environments based on Linux. This repository provides a X11 Linux Desktop environment for the development of the XPlatformer project.</description></item><item><title>xsamples</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-xsamples/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:46:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-xsamples/</guid><description>XSamples provides a collection of XWindows starter code that works with the XGameLib library. XSamples Summary XSamples provides a collection of XWindows starter code that works with the XGameLib library. The XGameLib library powers the XPlatformer project. All the examples make use of the XLib API (XOrg) and focus on code that was developed in the XPlatformer project (or planned to be used). The point of the examples is to demonstrate how to use the XGameLib library.</description></item><item><title>xgamelib</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-xgamelib/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:46:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-xgamelib/</guid><description>XGameLib is a simple video game library used in the development of a classic side-scrolling arcade game, using the XLib API. The point of the game is to control a character through a terrain to meet an objective. The project makes use of the XLib API (XOrg) and focus on code that was developed to accomplish tasks for the assignment task.</description></item><item><title>xplatformer</title><link>/2017/05/xplatformer-xplatformer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 22:44:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2017/05/xplatformer-xplatformer/</guid><description>XPlatformer is a simple video game reminiscent of the classic side-scrolling arcade game, using the XLib API. The point of the game is to control a character through a terrain to meet an objective. The project makes use of the XLib API (XOrg) and focus on code that was developed to accomplish tasks for the assignment task. &lt;img src="./docs/screenshots/xplatformer.png" alt="xplatformer" title="XPlatformer"></description></item></channel></rss>